<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web development on Intro to Computer-Science Berlin 2021</title>
    <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web development on Intro to Computer-Science Berlin 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>25/March - Basic knowledge of HTML</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_html/</guid>
      <description>Preparations 1. Review exercises from Version Control with Git and GitHub (11/March) Reivew the content from the Git and GitHub lecture. We&#39;ll use github to store the HTML files we create in this lecture.
Review Version Control with Git and GitHub: 11/March 2. Review exercises from Using an IDE (Integrated development environment) (18/March) Review the content from last lecture on Using an IDE with VsCode. We&#39;ll use VsCode to work on creating HTML files in this lecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30/March - Basic knowledge of CSS (Cascading Style Sheet)</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_css/</guid>
      <description>Preparations 1. Watch these Videos  Why Is CSS So Weird? - Theory &amp;amp; history Learn CSS in 20 Minutes - Practice Learn CSS Flexbox 15 Minutes - Practice Learn CSS Grid 20 Minutes - Practice  2. HTML class practice repository on Github We&#39;ll continue to apply some style to the journal we started building in our previous session Basic HTML
 https://github.com/ReDI-School/ber-intro-to-cs-2021-html-journal   Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Lesson Agenda and Goals 5 minutes ❌   Live demo on basic CSS 25 minutes Preparations section   Kahoot on basics of html and css 15 minutes Preparations section   Review CSS Activity task as a whole class 10 minutes ❌   Class break 10 minutes ❌   CSS Activity (in smaller groups) 45-60 minutes VsCode and Git installed    Lesson Goal Understand what CSS is, why we use it and how we can apply it to style HTML pages</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
