<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Berlin 2021 - Intro to Computer Science on Intro to Computer-Science Berlin 2021</title>
    <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Berlin 2021 - Intro to Computer Science on Intro to Computer-Science Berlin 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>04/October - Basic knowledge of HTML</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_html/</guid>
      <description>Preparations 1. Review exercises from Version Control with Git and GitHub (21/September) Reivew the content from the Git and GitHub lecture. We&#39;ll use github to store the HTML files we create in this lecture.
Review Version Control with Git and GitHub: 21/September 2. Review exercises from Using an IDE (Integrated development environment) (30/September) Review the content from last lecture on Using an IDE with VsCode. We&#39;ll use VsCode to work on creating HTML files in this lecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07/October - Basic knowledge of CSS (Cascading Style Sheet)</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_css/</guid>
      <description>Preparations 1. Watch these Videos  Why Is CSS So Weird? - Theory &amp;amp; history Learn CSS in 20 Minutes - Practice Learn CSS Flexbox 15 Minutes - Practice Learn CSS Grid 20 Minutes - Practice  2. HTML class practice repository on Github We&#39;ll continue to apply some style to the journal we started building in our previous session Basic HTML
 https://github.com/ReDI-School/ber-intro-to-cs-2021-html-journal   Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Lesson Agenda and Goals 5 minutes ❌   Questions from last session 15 minutes ❌   Live demo on basic CSS 25 minutes Preparations section   Review CSS Activity task as a whole class 10 minutes ❌   Class break 10 minutes ❌   CSS Activity (in smaller groups) 45-60 minutes VsCode and Git installed    Lesson Goal Understand what CSS is, why we use it and how we can apply it to style HTML pages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12/October - Practical Demonstration of HTML and CSS</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/html_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/html_css/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Review the CSS course content, and watch this video (if you haven&#39;t already): Learn CSS in 20 Minutes Review the HTML course content, check out this video (start at 7:30 and end at 49:35 unless you&#39;d like to learn about semantic tags :-) ) Decide who to build a website for (you? your pet? someone else?). Pick a simple background image for your website. You can choose a landscape photo you’ve taken or search for images that are free to use e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13/April - Practice Javascript, HTML and CSS</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/practice_html_css_js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/practice_html_css_js/</guid>
      <description>Preparations  Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Intro to Lesson 5 minutes ❌   Practical Activity (in smaller groups) 40-50 minutes VsCode and Git installed   Checkout 5 minutes ❌    Lesson Goal Practice what we&#39;ve learned so far!
We&#39;re going to make use of the command line, HTML, CSS and Javascript to create a web page that displays the time and date!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14/October - Basic knowledge of Javascript</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/web/basic_js/</guid>
      <description>Preparations  A short intro to JavaScript Detailed video from AmigosCode starting from Beginners going all the way to advanced - watch from 12:15 till 56:23 and from 1:10:15 till 1:16:03 📚 An intro to JavaScript from Mozilla A small number guessing game   Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Lesson Agenda and Goals 5 minutes ❌   Live demo on basic JS 45 minutes Preparations section   Review of the Activity task as a whole class 10 minutes ❌   Class break 10 minutes ❌   JS Activity (in smaller groups) 45-60 minutes VsCode and Git installed    Lesson Goal To gain familiarity with what JavaScript is, what it can do, and how it fits into a web site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02/04/November - Installing Python</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/installing_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/installing_python/</guid>
      <description>Pre Requisites  Review the course content from last class and bring any questions you have ! We will answer these questions at the beginning of class. (Remember, if you have a question, so does someone else in the class, so please feel free to ask :) ) Review 26/October - Introduction to Python Read through the Python Installation Overview section below. Spend some time thinking about which option may make sense for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11/16/November - Practical Python Session</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/practical_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/practical_python/</guid>
      <description>Pre Requisites   Review the course content from last class, and try to continue going through the exercises! If you get stuck on any of them, no problem -- make a note of this so we can review these tasks at the beginning of class on Thursday.
Review 02/November - Installing Python   (Optional) create a repository (local and remote) to gather your Python exercises from last class. Add and commit the file to the repository, and then push these to GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14/Sept - Inspiration class </title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/file_system/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/file_system/intro/</guid>
      <description>Pre Requisites Create an account in code.org website
 https://studio.code.org/users/sign_up  Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Teacher/Student introduction 20-30 mins ❌   Showing the outline of the course: 5-10 mins ❌   Intro to computer science: 20-30 minutes ❌   Small break 5mins ❌   Dance Party 20-30 mins Register code.org   Small introduction to what is software/code 20-30 mins ❌   Next class overview 5 mins ❌    Extra resources  Intro to computer science Harvard - Binary Exploring how computers work How do computers remember History of computer science Scratch Presentation   Next class preparation Operating systems &amp;amp; Command Line Basics Part 1 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14/Sept - Operating Systems &amp; Command Line Basics</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/file_system/command_line_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/file_system/command_line_part1/</guid>
      <description>Pre Requisites Create an account on repl.it
 https://repl.it/signup  Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Operating system (OS) basics 20-25 minutes ❌   Principle of abstraction 5-10 minutes ❌   Graphical &amp;amp; command line interfaces to OS 5-10 minutes ❌   Linux file system hierarchy 5-10 minutes repl.it account   Class break 10 minutes ❌   The Linux command line 35-40 minutes repl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16/March - Review Git and Command Line; Intro to the Internet</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/git/review_git_command_line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/git/review_git_command_line/</guid>
      <description>We will spend the first part of class going over how the internet works conceptually and then spend the rest of the session doing practical exercises using Git, GitHub, and the command line.
Prerequisites 1. Watch these Videos These videos from Khan Academy&#39;s Internet 101 series will give you a high-level overview of how the internet works. Please try to take notes on the questions below each video; we will go over these in class as well, but they cover the main points from the videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16/September/2021 - Command Line Basics Part 2</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/file_system/command_line_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/file_system/command_line_part2/</guid>
      <description>Pre Requisites  Watch this video on files and file Systems  If this video was difficult to understand or you are unfamiliar with navigating the file system on your computer currently, we recommend that you watch this video and this followup video   Watch this video until 8:30 on file paths (Optional): watch this video on the history of keyboards and the command line interface (Optional - for Windows users only): install the Cmder console emulator (easier) or set up the windows subsystem for linux  Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Kahoot 15 minutes videos   Questions from Kahoot + Session 1 15 minutes ❌   Useful Terms/Concepts 5-10 minutes videos   Navigate file system and working with files &amp;amp; folders (demo) 10-15 minutes ❌   Quick overview of package managers 5-10 minutes ❌   Class break 10 minutes ❌   Command line practice in groups 40-50 minutes local terminal OR repl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18/November - Object-oriented Python</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/python_classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/python_classes/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  You have completely set up one of the three Python development options  VsCode PyCharm Google Colab Notebook   You have solved the tasks from the last class   Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Lesson Goals 5 minutes ❌   Check-in on pre-reqs and questions from last class 15 minutes ❌   Procedural programming 10 minutes ❌   Object-oriented Programming 10 minutes ❌   Pillars of object-oriented programming 10 minutes ❌   Break 10 minutes ❌   Task: Extend the pet clinic example 20 minutes ❌   Bonus Task: Implement a REDI Course Management System 20 minutes ❌   Check-out 10 minutes ❌    0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21/September - Version Control with Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/git/git_and_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/git/git_and_github/</guid>
      <description>1. Install Git 💾 First! Check if you already have git installed, open your command line and run:
1git --version If you see something like the following output then you already have git installed:
1git version 2.x.x Otherwise, here are instructions to install Git:
 For Windows For MacOS  2. Sign up to GitHub 🚀 Sign up here: https://github.com/join
Why?
 We will use it in the class to store our code It can be used to collaborate with others It can be used to showcase your work  3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23/November - Object-oriented Python</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/python_classes_practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/python_classes_practical/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Review the following concepts from the previous class and answer the following questions:  What is object orientated programming Difference between an Object and a Class How do we define a constructor function How do we define attributes on a class How do we create a method on a class How do we create an inhertiance class   [Recommended]: Work on the bonus task (task 6) from the previous class [Optional]: review the w3 schools&#39; materials on Python classes   Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Lesson Goals 5 minutes ❌   Check-in on pre-reqs, recap, questions from last class 10 - 15 minutes ❌   Kahoot 10 - 15 minutes ❌   Exercises in groups 30 minutes ❌   Break 10 minutes ❌   Exercises in groups 40 minutes ❌   Check-out 10 minutes ❌    0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25/November - Project Overview &amp; Adventures in Python</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/adventures_in_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/adventures_in_python/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  [Optional]: Finish the materials from the previous lesson   Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Check-in on questions from last class 5 minutes ❌   Lesson Goals 5 minutes ❌   Final Project Overview &amp;amp; Brainstorming 20-60 minutes ❌   Break 10 minutes ❌   Kahoot 10 - 15 minutes ❌   Start working through Python activity rest of class ❌    Check-In Respond to the post on the class slack channel responding to the following question:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26/October - Introduction to Python</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/intro_to_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/python/intro_to_python/</guid>
      <description>Pre Requisites None for today!
 Class Curriculum    Section content Expected time (mins) Pre - Requirements     Check-in and questions from last class 5 minutes ❌   Lesson Goals 5 minutes ❌   Python Overview 15 minutes ❌   Hands-on Python exercise (in pairs) 45-60 minutes ❌   Break 10 minutes ❌   Synthesis of Python Concepts from Exercise 15-30 minutes ❌   (Possible) &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot; in Python Exercise 20 minutes ❌   Check-out 5 minutes ❌    Lesson Goal Have a high-level idea of what Python is and start getting comfortable reading and writing basic statements in this programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30/September - Using an IDE (Integrated development environment)</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/git/ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/docs/git/ide/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites 1. Install VsCode Visual Studio Code is a freeware source-code editor made by Microsoft for Windows, Linux and macOS. Features include support for debugging, syntax highlighting, intelligent code completion, snippets, code refactoring, and embedded Git. Wikipedia
During this course, while working with HTML and Pything we might end up working with an code editor to make easier interacting with files and folder. An editor can be considered the notebook of a programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redi-school.github.io/ber-dcp-intro-to-computer-science/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
